hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our
obstacles topic let's look at our next
test automation obstacle which is called
lots of rows now in this obstacle uh we
need to count the rows in the table and
we need to input the count into the text
field which is called the row count and
after that uh we need to click on the
button okay so these are the three tasks
which we need to perform as you can see
uh this table has got around five rows
so you can count them and then uh we
need to uh write five here in the row
count and then click me okay so this is
what uh we need to do through Automation
and as you can see the table is dynamic
so once I clicked on clickme the number
of rows again changed right so you
cannot just uh go ahead and do a static
way of counting the rows you need to put
a dynamic way of counting the rows and
then you need to enter it into the row
count so let's see how we can do this uh
in
tosa so coming back to tosa uh let's go
ahead and now create our module so I'm
going to scan this
application and here we are going to
select all the three um objects which we
require so we require the table we
require the text box and then we require
the button or link which is called click
me okay and then let me also rename this
uh so that we we can find the
obstacle and here and then save and
close
it okay and now coming back to our test
cases so let's create another test case
here for the obstacle and then we are
going to add the module into this
particular obstacle test case so let's
go back here and drag our module here we
you can see the table uh the text box
and the button
right so here what we need to do is use
a property called row count okay so tosa
provides you uh two properties one is
row count one is column count uh in a
table element using which you can easily
find the number of rows and number of
columns in the table okay so for this uh
we will use the row count property here
which which will be equals to a buffer
because we'll be buffering that
particular value okay so that uh we
don't have any static values here it
will always be dynamic okay so I'm going
to call this
rows and then uh I'm going to make this
buffer okay so you can see uh it will
calculate the row count and then it will
pass it on to the buffer which is called
Rose okay and then we can use that
buffer to enter it into the text Fields
so we'll use B of
row and then finally we are going to
click on this particular link okay so
it's a pretty simple obstacle um you
just need to know that you can use the
rowon property to count the number of
rows in any particular table okay so now
I'm going to change this work state to
complete it and now we can go ahead and
execute this
okay so as you can see it counted the
number of rows which is 10 and then it
entered it into the text box and then it
clicked on the button and this completed
the particular obstacle okay so this is
how you can use uh the property row
count or column count to count the
number of rows and columns uh which are
present in the table it may be a dynamic
or a static table TOs will anyway count
the number of rows and return the number
of rows which can be buffered and stored
in a buffer uh value which can be used
uh in later steps in your test
cases that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video